<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<refentry
version="5.0"
xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
><refmeta
><refentrytitle
>Docbook::Convert</refentrytitle
><manvolnum
>3</manvolnum
></refmeta
><refnamediv
><refname
>Docbook::Convert</refname
><refpurpose
>Convert Docbook articles and refentry's to other formats such as Markup and POD</refpurpose
></refnamediv
><refsynopsisdiv
><programlisting
><command
># Use on file handle
#
use Docbook::Convert;
open FILE, 'docbook.xml' or die $!;
print Docbook::Convert-&gt;markdown(*FILE);
print Docbook::Convert-&gt;pod(*FILE);

# Use on existing file
#
print Docbook::Convert-&gt;markdown_file('docbook.xml');

# Use on existing string
#
print Docbook::Convert-&gt;markdown($docbook);

# Specify output options
#
print Docbook::Convert-&gt;markdown($docbook, { meta_display_top=&gt;1 });</command
></programlisting
></refsynopsisdiv
><refsection
><title
>Description</title
><para
>Docbook::Convert Perl will convert between Docbook and other foirmats - currently Markdown and POD. It is intended to let authors write documentation in Docbook, and then output it to more easily publishable formats such as Markdown - or have it converted to POD and optionally merged into a perl programs or module.</para
><para
>It currently supports as subset of Docbook tags and its intent is to convert Docbook 4+ article and refentry templates with common entites into manual pages or other documentation.</para
></refsection
><refsection
><title
>Methods</title
><para
>The following public methods are supplied:</para
><variablelist
><varlistentry
><term
>process($xml, \%opt)</term
><listitem
><para
>Convert an XML string or file handle into a different format. Unless directed via the handler option to default conversion will be to Markdown</para
></listitem
></varlistentry
><varlistentry
><term
>process_file($filename, \%opt)</term
><listitem
><para
>Convert an XML file - specified in $filename - into a different format. As per the process method the default convertsion if not otherwise specified will be Markdown.</para
></listitem
></varlistentry
><varlistentry
><term
>markdown($xml, \%opt)</term
><listitem
><para
>A shortcut to the process method with the Markdown handler implied</para
></listitem
></varlistentry
><varlistentry
><term
>markdown_file</term
><listitem
><para
>A shortcut to the process_file method with the Markdown handler implied</para
></listitem
></varlistentry
><varlistentry
><term
>pod($xml, \%opt)</term
><listitem
><para
>A shortcut to the process method with the POD handler implied</para
></listitem
></varlistentry
><varlistentry
><term
>pod_file($xml, \%opt)</term
><listitem
><para
>A shortcut to the process_file method with the POD handler implied</para
></listitem
></varlistentry
></variablelist
></refsection
><refsection
><title
>Options</title
><para
>The following options can be supplied to the process methods as a hash reference:</para
><variablelist
><varlistentry
><term
>meta_display_top</term
><listitem
><para
>If the Docbook Refentry or Article contains metadata (author, publication date etc.) display it at the top of the file in "key: value" format. By default metadata is not displayed. Supply as boolean.</para
></listitem
></varlistentry
><varlistentry
><term
>meta_display_bottom</term
><listitem
><para
>As per meta_display_top but output at bottom.</para
></listitem
></varlistentry
><varlistentry
><term
>meta_display_title</term
><listitem
><para
>If the metadata is to be prefixed with a title supply as a string.</para
></listitem
></varlistentry
><varlistentry
><term
>meta_display_title_h_style</term
><listitem
><para
>If a title is supplied the option will set which heading style is used to generate it. By default output is the equivalent of "Heading 1". Supported values are 'h1' through to 'h4'</para
></listitem
></varlistentry
><varlistentry
><term
>no_html</term
><listitem
><para
>Do not comingle HTML with the generated output. For some output handlers where the desired output outcome is not available natively HTML may be supplied (e.g. Markdown). Setting this option to 1 will suppress any HTML output. Naturally this may limit the completeness of any conversion</para
></listitem
></varlistentry
><varlistentry
><term
>no_image_fetch</term
><listitem
><para
>For some Docbook image entities attributes that control the scaling of images may be supplied. If they are found in some cases the images may need to be fetched to generate the appropriate HTML width paramaters. Setting this option to 1 will suppress any remote image fetching and thus will disable any image scaling in conversions.</para
></listitem
></varlistentry
><varlistentry
><term
>no_warn_unhandled</term
><listitem
><para
>By default Docbook entites that are not handled in the conversion process (because the code does not yet cater for them) generate a warning. Setting this option to 1 will suppress any warnings.</para
></listitem
></varlistentry
></variablelist
></refsection
></refentry
>
